Claret Nnamocha

Software Engineer

With about 4 years of experience as a full-stack (back-end heavy) developer working with Python, Node, and Typescript, and experience spanning e-commerce, fin-tech, media, and more, I possess the necessary skill set to approach and tackle any problem I encounter.

devclareo@gmail.com

+2349034116102

Owerri, Nigeria

claretnnamocha.com

linkedin.com/in/claretnnamocha in

github.com/claretnnamocha

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack Software Engineer

Zenolynk Technologies

07/2021 - Present

Lagos, Nigeria

Achievements/Tasks

- Building front end from UI/UX design
- Implementing Back-end API endpoints
- Maintaining already existing front end apps

Lead Software Engineer

PunchBet

07/2021 - 10/2021

Remote

PunchBet Is A Crypto Sports Betting Exchange with a supersimple interface that lets you bet your favourite sports team via a p2p betting system.

Achievements/Tasks

- Integrating cryptocurrency wallets for receiving and sending cryptocurrencies
- Generating blockchain wallet addresses on the ethereum network using mnemonics
- Delivering great back-end features on time and with quality
- Integrating the use of injected web3 (metamask) to receive and send cryptocurrencies

Software Engineer

Earnathon

11/2020 - Present

Lagos, Nigeria

Earn cryptocurrencies by taking courses and answering quizzes

Achievements/Tasks

- Integrating cryptocurrency wallets for receiving and sending cryptocurrencies.
- Delivering great back-end features on time and with quality.
- Integrating internal wallets for cryptocurrency withdrawal.

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

NICERT Expert Consulting (06/2021 - 07/2021)

- NICERT GROUP is a private limited liability company in partnership with Ecocert Group France and has been incorporated under Nigerian laws to provide conformity assessment and certification services in Nigeria for goods, products and services heading out of Nigeria to international markets.
- Developing REST APIs supporting several portals, platforms, and custom web apps.

Afrimart (04/2021 - Present) 🗗

- A Multi-tenancy eCommerce solution
- Developing REST APIs supporting several portals, platforms, and custom web apps

Amajudy (11/2020 - 12/2020) 🗹

- Buy and sell cryptocurrency
- Building and integrated internal wallets for users
- Integrating third-party payment providers to enable fiat and cryptocurrency deposits and withdrawals

Quizra (04/2020 - 06/2020) 🗹

- A Trivia mobile game
- Integrating a lot of third-party payment providers to enable fiat deposits and withdrawals
- Integrating a lot of third-party real time libraries to enable realtime multi-player gaming

Pytonik (02/2020 - Present)

A python framework built to enhance web development fast and easy, also help web developers to build more apps with less codes.

ScenicPlots (11/2018 - 11/2020) 🗗

- A potpourri of stories interlaced from various storytellers of all pedigree; Nobel literature laureates, newbie authors, from different parts of the globe, writing in every translatable language
- Building and integrated internal fiat wallets
- Integrating third-party payment providers to enable fiat deposits and withdrawal

ACHIEVEMENTS

Assistant Software Director, National Association of Computer Science Student (South East Zone) (10/2019 - 10/2020)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

WAYA Multi Links

11/2020 - 05/2021

Lagos, Nigeria

Waya Paychat digital wallet is an all-in-one platform to perform safe and secure transactions, pay your bills and socialize with friends and family

Achievements/Tasks

- Integrating internal wallets for users and merchants
- Collaborating with a team of software developers to build APIs and SDKs for payment solutions
- Delivering great back-end features on time and with quality
- Developing, deploying, and managing various forms of micro-services
- Implementing security features and middlewares

Contact: Stanley Okegbe - stantoju@gmail.com

Backend Engineer

JENSIV LTD

11/2018 - 11/2020

Owerri, Nigeria

We are an IT firm in Nigeria, made up of professional software engineers that utilize advanced software technologies to serve client needs.

Achievements/Tasks

- I worked in a team of software developers to build APIs for a telemedicine service that uses the Django framework.
- I created REST APIs for a literature-based application and web app using the Django framework alongside two other software developers.
- Created a multiplayer trivia mobile app.

Contact: Chijindu lwuchukwu - jendy36@gmail.com

Python Tutor (Internship)

Aptech Computer Education

10/2018 - 01/2019

Owerri, Nigeria

Achievements/Tasks

- Teaching a python programming language class from essential to intermediate level.
- Building several python applications as tools for learning the Python programming language.
- Creating a curriculum used in the learning process.

Contact: Fegor Idoro - idorofegor@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science

Imo State Universitu

09/2015 - 09/2021

Owerri, Nigeria

Courses

Computer Science

LANGUAGES

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Igbo Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Travelina

Playing games

Photography